If bootstrap sampling seems pretty amazing,
إذا كان أخذ العينات يبدو مذهلًا،
that's because it kind of is.
فهذا يرجع إلى نوعها.
But the application of bootstrap sampling actually goes beyond even the use cases here.
ولكن تطبيق أخذ العينات يتجاوز حتى حالات الاستخدام هنا.
Bootstrapping techniques have been used for leading machine learning algorithms.
تم استخدام تقنيات أخذ العينات لريادة خوارزمية تعلم الآلة.
More on this as provided in the instructor notes below.
المزيد عن هذا على النحو المنصوص عليه في ملاحظات المعلم أدناه.
This technique is credited to Bradley Efron in 1979,
يعود الفضل في هذا الأسلوب إلى برادلي إفرون في عام 1979،
a Minnesota born statistician.
وهو عالم إحصائي ولد في ولاية مينيسوتا.
The name bootstrapping was given to the technique
تم إعطاء اسم أخذ العينات للطريقة
because of the amazement and how well it works is similar to
نظرًا لدهشتها ومدى نجاحها بطريقة تشبه
the idea of being able to walk into quicksand and pull
فكرة القدرة على السير في الرمال المتحركة
yourself out of the quicksand to safety by your own bootstraps.
وسحب نفسك من الرمال المتحركة إلى الأمان بواسطة الحذاء الخاص بك.
The way we can draw inference about a population parameter by only
إن الطريقة التي يمكننا بها استخلاص الاستدلال على معلمة السكان من خلال
performing repeated sampling within our existing sample is just as amazing.
إجراء أخذ العينات المتكررة فقط داخل نموذجنا الحالي مذهلة للغاية.
We actually gain confidence about where parameter is likely
نحن في الواقع نكتسب الثقة حول مكان وجود المعلمة على الأرجح
to exist without having to collect any additional data.
دون الحاجة إلى جمع أي بيانات إضافية.
This is an amazing concept and it's wowed people for years.
هذا مفهوم مدهش وأبهر الناس لسنوات.